准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
亲人两行泪
分镜总监
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
技术总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
今天是裤头村一个非常特别的日子
It is a very special day in Bikini Bottom
我准备好了
I'm ready
我准备好了  我准备好了
I'm ready, I'm ready
派大星  我知识助记卡片你带了没
Patrick, did you bring my flashcards?
带了呢  兄弟
Right here, buddy
过驾考要用到的所有知识都在卡片上
Everything you need to pass the test is on these cards
不要  派大星
No, Patrick
学习的味道真不错
Learning tastes good
派大星  我还得用啊
Patrick, I needed those
胡说八道
Fiddlesticks
你驾考考的次数比谁都多
You've taken that driving test more times than anyone
都57次了
57 times
那58就是你的幸运数字
Well then, 58 is your lucky number
驾考你非过不可  海绵宝宝
You're gonna pass that driving test, SpongeBob
因为你是大赢家
because you're a winner
我是大赢家吗
I'm a winner?
谁是大赢家
Who's a winner?
我是大赢家
I'm a winner
谁是大赢家
Who's a winner?
我是大赢家
I'm a winner
谁是大赢家
Who's a winner?
我是大赢家
I'm a winner
我是大赢家  我是大赢家
I'm a winner, I'm a winner
滑浪学校
一分三十七秒后
考得怎么样  大赢家
How'd you do, winner?
驾照给我看看
Let's see that license
驾照没考到  派大星
I didn't get a license, Patrick
驾照到时候是要邮寄给你吗
Are they gonna mail it to you?
不对  派大星
No, Patrick
我驾考挂科了
I failed the boating test
到头来58并不是我的幸运数字
I guess 58 wasn't my lucky number, after all
不会吧
No way
58可是史上最幸运的数字了
58 is, like, the luckiest number ever
这驾考一定有暗箱操作
The test must be rigged
还是回家吧  派大星
Let's just go home, Patrick
我没查明白  就哪都别想去
We're not goin' anywhere until I get to the bottom of this
我要亲自来考试
I'm takin' that test myself
不要  派大星
No, Patrick
我都已经练了好多年了
I've been training for years
他们会生吞你的
They'll eat you alive
别闹了  海绵宝宝
Please, SpongeBob
我很清楚自己在干嘛
I think I know what I'm doing
不要  派大星
No, Patrick
不要
No
早安
Good morning
你别想评判我
You're not the judge of me
我考官当然得评判了
Actually, I am
考试现在开始
Let the testing begin
我不该让他考的
I shouldn't have let him do it
我还算什么朋友
What kind of friend am I?
海绵宝宝  海绵宝宝
SpongeBob, SpongeBob
我在你身边  兄弟
I'm here for you, buddy
我驾考过了
I passed my test
你这是满分了
You got a perfect score?
对啊
Yeah
你不是说过很难吗
I thought you said it was hard
满
Perfect
分
score
走了
Come on
我得给我的新驾照去拍证件照了
I've gotta get my picture taken for my new license
站在线后面  先生
Stand behind the line, sir
我样子如何
How do I look?
像个大赢家
Like a winner
好了没
Ready?
好了
Ready
恭喜
恭喜你  派大星先生
Congratulations, Mr. Star
你是第一百万个通过驾考的考生
You're the one-millionth person to pass the test
所以是不是要送免费钥匙链给我
Does that mean I get a free key chain?
不对
No
要送你一辆全新汽船
You get a brand-new boatmobile
全新炸鲈三千终极汽船
The new bass blaster 3000
the ultimate boating machine
好耶
Yeah, all right
美女会想要你
Women will want you
帅哥会想成为你
Men will want to be you
朋友都会嫉妒你
You'll be the envy of your friends
是不是很棒啊
Isn't this great?
我考到了驾照  赢到了新船
I got my license and a new boat
我
I'm
真
so
为你
happy
高兴
for you
喇叭能响
The horn works
今天简直是史上最棒的一天
This is the greatest day ever
对不对  海绵宝宝
right, SpongeBob?
对  派大星
Right, Patrick
根本想不出能让今天好转的事
I can't think of one thing
that would make this day better
考到驾照那个不算
Except maybe getting my license
要是你亲自去考的话
Maybe if you apply yourself
就有可能刚好第两百万个考到驾照了
you could be the two-millionth person
to get his license
第两百万
Two-millionth?
然后就有可能跟我一样免费领新船了
Then you could get a free boat, just like me
对对对  就跟你一样
Yeah, "just like you"
我想激励别人
I try to serve as an inspiration to others
还回不回家了
Can we go home now?
都已经绕着你家开好几小时了
We've been drivin' around your house for hours
对啊
I know
比走路快上个不少呢  对不对
It's a lot faster than walking, isn't it?
谢谢你送我一程  派大星
Thanks for the ride, Patrick
没事  兄弟
No problem, buddy
反正你也只能当个
You can't help being a
行人
pedestrian
派大星  你在干什么
Patrick, what are you doing?
我要修我船
I'm trying to work on my boatmobile
能不能给我小点声
Now, could you keep it down?
现在凌晨三点  别人还得睡觉
It's 3:00 in the morning, people are trying to sleep
都四点了
4:00
这个点了谁在按门
Who could be at the door at this-
什
Wha-
又怎么了  派大星
Now what is it, Patrick?
你绝对猜不到我今天怎么了
You will never guess what happened to me today
你考到驾照了
You got your license?
猜对了
Yeah
裤头村驾照
派大星
不过还有哦
But that's not all
你领到了新船
You got a new boat
又对了
Yeah
你不会一直在跟踪我吧
Have you been followin' me?
管好你自己的事
You know, you need to get your own life
我只想睡上个几分钟
I just need a few minutes sleep
对  小蜗
Yes, Gary
他的新船我都看到了
I saw his new boat
累死我了
So tired
兄弟  要搭便船上班吗
Hey, buddy, need a ride to work?
谢了  派大星
Thanks, Patrick
不过我宁愿走路去上班
but I'd rather walk to work
蟹堡王
原来没驾照的生活有那么空虚啊
Boy, I never realized how empty life is without a license
多谢你送我一程
Thanks for the ride
没事  兄弟
No problem, buddy
等你考到驾照就能送我一程了
You can give me rides once you get your license
应该说是  假如你考到驾照
I mean, if you get your license
够了  再也不坐派大星开的船了
That's it, I am through driving around with Patrick
要是再让我看到一艘船
If I have to see one more boatmobile
海绵宝宝  你负责接得来速的单
SpongeBob, you're mannin' the drive-through
啥时候开的得来速
When did we get a drive-through?
我发现最近不少小年轻都忙个不停
I realize there's a lot of young people
"on the go" these days
没空好好坐下好好吃一顿
They don't have time to sit down and eat
而是忙着行驶在开阔的道路上
They're too busy, out on the open road
活出自己的梦想
livin' their dreams
我以前也有过梦想
I used to have a dream
是吗
Yeah?
我以前还得过肾结石呢
I used to have a kidney stone
一切总都会过去的
Everything passes eventually
别做白日梦了  工作谋生吧
Now, stop dreamin', and work for a livin'
欢迎光临蟹堡王  我可以
Welcome to the Krusty Krab, may I-
喇叭还能响
The horn still works
开
关
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
干嘛戴头盔  派大星
What's with the helmet, Patrick?
我既然已经是个专业司机了
Well, since I'm now an expert driver
就得好好改造一下形象
I have to keep up my image
天啊  开船可真简单
Boy, driving is so easy
要我教你吗
Do you want me to give you lessons?
那可太棒了
That would be great
派大星
Patrick
公交
妈妈好  爸爸好
Hi, mommy, hi, daddy
派大星  得跟你说多少次
Patrick, how many times do we have to tell you?
我们是海绵宝宝的爸妈  不是你爸妈
We're SpongeBob's mom and dad, not yours
什么
What?
原来我是孤儿吗
I'm an orphan?
不过猜怎么着
But guess what
裤头村驾照
派大星
我驾考过了
I passed my driver's test
太棒了  派大星
That's great, Patrick
海绵宝宝又挂科了  千万别提那事
SpongeBob failed his test, so don't mention it
我们很会避雷的
We know how to stay clear of that minefield
妈
Mom
我要带走路宝宝回家去了
Well, I've gotta take Mr. Walks-a-lot back home
他老是找我搭便船呢
He's always askin' for rides
连派大星都能考到驾照
Even Patrick has a license
来看看这宝贝能干嘛
Let's see what this baby can do
限速40迈
派大星  这边限速40迈
Patrick, the speed limit is 40 miles per hour
对对对
Yeah, yeah
四十迈半了
Forty-and-a-half miles per hour
都快41迈了
That's almost 41 miles per hour
他超速了
He's speeding
派大星
Patrick
停车
Stop this car
啥
What
哪
where
谁
who?
警官  我要尽自己的公民义务
Officer, it is my civic duty
举报这艘船的司机超速
to report that the driver of this vehicle is speeding
快用测速枪测他速
Why don't you clock him with your radar gun?
好吧
OK
他其实才开了40迈  没超速
Actually, he's going 40 miles under the limit
你这打小报告的快滚  不然抓你坐牢
So move along before I run you in, tattletale
你确定不抓他坐牢吗
Are you sure you don't wanna run him in?
那是红灯  派大星
That's a red light, Patrick
派大星
Patrick
你都连闯三个红灯了
You just ran three red lights
又怎样
So?
你应该停船才对
You're supposed to stop
天才司机很清楚自己在干什么
I think the driving genius knows what he's doing
天才司机
Driving genius?
天才会非法调头吗
Would a genius make an illegal u-turn?
会飙进孤儿院吗
Through an orphanage?
里面的人早及时逃出来了
They ran for it in time
你气什么气
What are you so mad about?
考到驾照的应该是我才对
I should've gotten that license
这船应该是我的才对
And this should be my boatmobile
怎么能这么说
How can you say that?
你要是我朋友
If you were my friend
我考到驾照就得为我高兴
you'd be happy for me getting my license
你要是我朋友
If you were my friend
就不会拿你驾照怼我脸
you wouldn't rub your license in my face
我才没拿我驾照怼你脸
I'm not rubbing my license in your face
这才叫拿我驾照怼你脸
This is rubbing my license in your face
给我
Give me that
我一生努力奋斗就为了这个
I've worked my whole life for this
你根本就不配
You don't deserve this
乱扔垃圾的
Litterbugs
所以我才要担任警察
This is why I joined the force
是警察
It's the police
靠边停船  乱扔垃圾的
Pull it over, litterbug
乱扔垃圾的
Litterbug?
不要
No
这下有逃犯抓了
I got me a runner
派大星  你这是在搞什么鬼
Patrick, what do you think you're doing?
不知道
I don't know
我都没驾照了
I don't have a license anymore
小心
Look out
安全驾驶
裤头村监狱
关90天
90 days
市级法院
希望你学到了教训  别乱扔垃圾了
And I hope you learned
a valuable lesson about littering
再见  兄弟
So long, buddy
别忘了喂小蜗
Don't forget to feed Gary
你有时候会忘了喂
Sometimes you forget to feed him
我干了什么好事
What have I done?
派大星坐牢肯定活不长
Patrick can't survive in prison
他太软弱了
He's too soft
等等
Wait
派大星是清白的
Patrick's innocent
是我撕了派大星的驾照车窗抛物的
I tore up Patrick's license and threw it out the window
我才是乱丢垃圾的
I'm the litterbug
抓我坐牢吧
Take me, instead
鉴于没有法律先例可循
Well, considerin' there's no legal precedent
管他呢
What the heck
关90天
90 days
偿还了社会债务后
裤头村监狱
派大星
Patrick
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
真高兴你驾考通过了
I'm glad you passed the test
真高兴你考到驾照了
I'm glad you have a license
我要证明给你看  特地给你做了这个
And to prove it, I made you this
裤头村
一辈子好兄弟
Pals forever
把它放到你船上吧  兄弟
Let's put it on your boatmobile, buddy
我早就没船了
I don't have a boatmobile anymore
什么
What?
船坏了  就扔了
It stopped workin', so I threw it away
指针指到了E
The needle was on "e"
没油
意思应该是结束吧
Yeah, I figured that must mean "end"
那这个东西要怎么办
Then what do we do with this?
这样行不
How's that?
行
Yeah
好了吗  兄弟
Ready, buddy?
好了  兄弟
Ready, pal
土皇帝
分镜总监
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
技术总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
什么事
Yeah?
您好  先生
Good day, sir
我是
I am
我可清楚你哪位了
I know exactly who you are
小蜗
跟小蜗共度黄金时光最美好了
There's nothing like
spending some quality time with my gar-gar
杰森  实话实说
Jason, I have to be honest
我已经有新欢了
There's someone else
爷爷
Grandpa?
海绵宝宝  救命
SpongeBob, help
他来抓我了
He's on to me
我没时间了
I don't have much time
里奇萨蒙斯健身指南
派大星  你干什么
Patrick, what're you doing?
我得把这些书都烧了
I have to get rid of these books
如何阅读
为什么
Why?
给你看看为什么
I'll show you why
看见他没
See him?
他是图书馆的
He's from the library
知道我有书逾期了没还
He knows about my overdue books
所以我就会被抓去坐牢
Which means I'm gonna get thrown in the big house
知道那是什么意思吧
And you know what that means
量小管饿的牢饭吗
Small-portion meals?
没错
Exactly
派大星  你放心
Patrick, don't you worry
我挺你到底
I got your back, man
你好
Hi, there
您好  年轻人
Salutations, young one
您不会刚好认识
Say, you wouldn't happen to know
住在这颗石头底下的海星吧
the starfish that lives under this rock, would you?
我一只海星都不认识
No, I don't know any starfish
就算我认识这位所谓的海星
Even if I did know this "alleged" starfish
派大星也不会逾期不还图书馆的书
Patrick wouldn't owe any overdue library books
您不认识派大星可真是遗憾
Well, it's too bad you don't know Patrick star
因为我是一名宫廷成员
because I am from the royal ministry
有礼物要送他
and have a gift for him
什么礼物
What is it?
好漂亮
Pretty
这简直是史上最难吃的礼物
This is the worst-tasting gift, ever
因为那礼物是用来戴的  不是吃的
That's because you're supposed to wear it, not eat it
让我给你看样东西
Allow me to show you something
就在这
It's here
我手上拿着的
What I hold in my hands
是张能追溯到好几世纪前的家谱
is a family tree that goes back centuries
变形虫王
霉菌后
一切起源于变形虫王与霉菌后的婚姻
It starts with the marriage
of king amoeba and queen mildew
历经数代近亲繁殖
Then, through a few inbred generations
血统最终延续到了您  派大星阁下
ends at you, sir Patrick
派大星
因此您正是王室的后裔
Which makes you a descendant of royalty
您就是王
You are a king
如今我将前去宫廷
And now, it's time I adjourned to the royal ministry
从此为您效劳  殿下
where I shall be at your service, your highness
派大星  太棒了
Patrick, that's great
哪棒了
What is?
你成国王了
That you're king
什么是国王
What's a king?
当了国王就能要什么有什么
When you're a king, you can get anything you want
要什么有什么吗
Anything I want?
海绵宝宝  你说咱能不能来点吃的
SpongeBob, do you think we could get somethin' to eat?
如你所愿  陛下
Your wish is my command, your majesty
各位市民
Good townspeople
让我们热烈欢迎新上任的国王
let us rejoice in welcoming our new king
国王特别想要吃的
King needs food, badly
这到底是想干
What's this all abou-
要我帮你干嘛呢  派大星
Well, well, well, what can I do for you, Patrick?
国王想要
The king would like-
闭嘴  海绵宝宝
Zip it, SquarePants
我跟富哥讲话  你别插嘴
I'm talking to the rich guy
我要来十个蟹黄堡
I'll have ten krabby patties
一杯蟹奶昔  大薯条
a krabby milkshake, large fries
我有个更好的点子
I've got a better idea
给国王量身定制的自助餐
A buffet fit for a king
好吃
Tasty
你听  派大星
Listen, Patrick
每个人的一生都要经历一段安定期
There comes a time in every man's life
when he's gotta settle down
也就是找老婆  生孩子
You know, get a wife, kids
把自己的钱全送给岳父
a father-in-law you give all of your money to
听着不错
That sounds great
能不能再来点番茄酱
Can I get a little more ketchup?
你不然先给我付账得了
How's about you pay the check, instead?
抱歉  蟹老板
Sorry, Mr. Krabs
不行
No can do
我可是裤头村之王
As king of Bikini Bottom
可以要什么有什么
I am allowed to have anything I want
对不对  海绵宝宝
Isn't that right, SpongeBob?
没错
That is correct
要什么有什么  而且全免费
Anything you want, and it's all free
全免费
All free?
谁都别想在我蟹堡王吃霸王餐
Nobody eats in me restaurant for free
管你是不是王
King or no king
那个你吃不吃
Are you gonna eat that?
打算吃  干嘛
I was planning to, why?
我要吃
I want it
你哪来的特权  敢抢走我的吃的
What gives you the right to take my food?
跟他说去  海绵宝宝
Tell 'him, SpongeBob
派大星  称王貌似不是这么回事吧
Pat, I'm not sure if this is what being king is all about
你不是说我要什么有什么吗
I thought you said I could have anything I want
我最最好的朋友是在骗我吗
Was my bestest friend lying to me?
别闹了  派大星
Don't be ridiculous, Patrick
我才不会骗你呢
I never lie to you
好
Good
快跟他说去
Now, tell him
嗨
Hi
宫廷有令
By proclamation of the royal ministry
宫廷
国王有权要什么有什么
the king is entitled to get whatever he wants
你这不公平
This isn't fair
人生本来就不公平
Life isn't fair, pal
你习惯去吧
Get used to it
总算到手了
I finally did it
终于集到了神奇太空鱼侠第二册
At long last, I've acquired
issue number two of wonder space fish
神奇
太空鱼侠
而且还全新未拆封
And in mint condition
这下不惑之年可算圆满了
Now my 40-year-old life
漫画书可也算是集齐了
and my comic book collection are complete
老妈一定会为我骄傲
Mom's gonna be so proud of me
骄个屁的傲  这些漫画书明明归我
No, she won't be, because these comic books are mine
可我一生都在收藏漫画书啊
But I spent my entire life collecting those
是啊  那你后半生给我哭丧去
Yeah, well now you can spend
the rest of your life crying about it
我就是王
I'm the king
我
I
这就
will
去哭
cry about it
找我老妈哭
Cry right to my mom
我就爱称王
I love being king
好  感谢先生
OK, thank you, sir
派大星肯定需要这个助步器
I'm sure king Patrick could use this walker
但愿如此
I hope so
连海神王都知道我需要
Neptune knows I did
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
是的  阁下
Yes, sire?
我需要你给点意见
I need your opinion on something
你觉得这平板电视
Do you think the giant flat screen TV
是应该搬到高贵蛋雕陈列那边
should go over the fancy egg display
还是室内游泳池那边
or the indoor swimming pool?
你好啊  阳光
Hello, sunshine
多美的早晨啊
What a beautiful morning
正正好
Just perfect
往后
Back
back
往后
Back
好
OK
可以了
Yeah, that's good
刚刚好
Perfect
什么  可可可我家
What, but, but, but, my house
我家是怎么
What's happened to my-
海绵宝宝  派大星
SpongeBob, Patrick
这里到底是怎么回事
What the barnacles is going on here?
看你们干了什么好事
Look at what you've done
看我家前院糟蹋成什么样了
Look at my poor front yard
就你家前院啊
Your front yard?
殿下正在建造一个皇家摩天轮
His royal highness is building a royal Ferris wheel
摩天轮吗
Ferris wheel?
对啊  是不是很棒
I know, isn't it great?
棒个屁  烂到没边了
No, it's not great, it's horrible
给我得了  停
That's it, stop
裤头村的居民们  停
People of Bikini Bottom, stop
停
Stop
派大星不是国王
Patrick's no king
看看他
Look at him
就这一坨粉东西  能当什么王
How can this pink blob be king?
你  难道真的相信那只无脑海星
You, can you honestly believe that
that mindless starfish
能称得上什么王吗
coud possibly be the king of anything?
土皇帝
King of morons
还差不多
Maybe
他可能说中了
He might be on to somethin'
对  对
Yeah, yeah
看看  看看
see, see, see, see
对  对
Yeah, yeah
对啊  凭什么要把自己家当都给他
Yeah, why are we givin' this guy all of our stuff?
看吧  看吧
See, see?
你才不是王
You're not a king
别人也都这么认为
And now they all think so, too
抓住他
Get him
进攻
Attack
海绵宝宝  抓住他
SpongeBob, get him
我就此下令
So I decree
进攻
Attack
得令  陛下
Right away, your majesty
章鱼哥
Squidward?
干嘛
What?
可不可以请你签下这份条约
Could I get you to sign this treaty
承诺永远效忠派大星国王吗
promising your eternal loyalty to king Patrick?
给我
Give me that
条约是吧
A treaty, huh?
这是我对你条约的看法
Well, here's what I think of your treaty
我的臣民抛弃了我
My royal subjects have deserted me
都怪那个垃圾章鱼哥
And it's all 'cause of that horrible Squidward
都是他的错
This is all his fault
怪他  怪他
His, his
不怪我  怪他
not mine, his
派大星  你是怎么了
Patrick, what's happened to you?
我不懂你什么意思
I don't know what you mean
跟你说吧
You know, actually
蟹老板估计不知道我跑哪了  然后
Mr. Krabs is probably wondering where I am, and-
然后干嘛
and what?
那个  就只是
And, well, it's just that, um
你有点乱来
you're kind of being a jerk
还以为你要说我滥用权力呢
I thought you were going to say I was abusing my power
那个  我
Well, I-
谁说我滥用权力了
Who's saying I'm abusing my power?
我要抓全镇居民你去坐牢
I'll put the whole town in prison
敢质疑我权威  就是叛国
Questioning my authority is treason
傻傻演说老半天  渴死我了
All these giggly speeches are making me thirsty
海绵宝宝  给我来点喝的
SpongeBob, I request a drink
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
大家都走了
Gee, everybody's gone
只剩我一个
I'm all alone
行  我自个找喝的
Fine, I'll get it myself
敲敲门
Knock, knock
要讲敲门笑话
A knock-knock joke
谁啊
Who's there?
你
You
我没听懂
I don't get it
我就是你  你就是我
I'm you, and you are me
我变什么玩意了
What have I become?
有畜生  畜生
A monster, monster
是  是你啊
It's, it's you
给  你拿走
Here, here, take it
我再也不要了
I don't want it anymore
它害我变畜生了
It's turned me into a monster
我应该知道是怎么回事
I think I know what's going on here
派大星  能力越大责任就越大
Patrick, with great power comes great responsibility
你不懂我刚说的大道理  对吧
You haven't a clue what I just told you, do you?
对
No
无妨
Well, just as well
我是来取回王冠的
I've come to take the crown back
似乎到头来你也并不是王室成员
as it would seem that you aren't royalty after all
我发现家谱上面沾了咖啡渍
I discovered this coffee stain
把它清干净就能看出来
which, upon removal, reveals
小蜗阁下才是真正的王位继承者
that sir Gary is the true heir to the king's crown
小蜗
你看看啊
Well, would you look at that
小蜗  你称王了
Gary, you're royalty